We are going to work on the facial practice, which in osteopathic concepts, is a concept
holistic.
This means we consider not just area A, B, C, and D; I use the environment
around me.
It's almost this environment that reorganizes me, you see, since I depend on this
environment.
All this reading we will do at the level of the face, the nails, is actually a reflection
of an indirect nature in relation to...
the neural crest. This means that the neural crest is a tissue that is both
informative,
so it receives information, but through this almost arachnoidal network
that it has in the body,
which can be found a bit in peripheral areas, in visceral terms. This means
that the face is the expression of the inside, and the face informs the inside.
When we look at the
mandibular arches, meaning at the moment when the emb...
will form this flexion, there will be what we call branchial pouches
that will be
lines of force on an almost cartilaginous level
or mesodermal that will orient towards the base
of the skull. This means that this base of the skull receives a convergence of
facial information
directly from both my
branchial structures and the packaging of my brain. It's a crossroads of
information that will
resonate on a glandular, circulatory level,
lymphatic and even on a
neurological axis. So remember, not only is this base of the
skull a balance
between my neurocranium and my viscerocranium, but all the information...
is given, providing us the lines of force of the practice, and we will see how we can rebalance
ultimately on a tension level, in osteopathic terms, the spheno-basilar symphysis
in
relation to this, which seeks simply to find the best adaptation. A thyroid that
is
not functioning well leads to hypomobilities. Remember, it's always about taking
and
I must be able to give; people who are congested are those who do not give
that will truly organize this level, and the entire face is a dynamic
movement of my brain, in development.
This means that initially, I actually have a prosencephalon, so the most
anterior part of my brain,
my encephalons, rhombencephalons, and then I have what is called the
spinal canal,
and it is essentially the prosencephalon that will generate a dynamic movement,
two small lateral bulbs that will "hypertrophy"
and will create a movement like this of
development. It will grow, and at a certain point, there is a brake in front, which will create
a
specific field to form the frontal, and then it will make such a movement of development like
this, like this, like this, like this, to form
a hemisphere on the left and on the right. In this phase,
a phase of straightening of the face
and this is where initially
my face, which was compressed
let's say practically
between my heart and my brain
will suddenly open up in this space
and that's how
the lateral regions like the
optic placode
here that was relatively lateral
will come to integrate forwards
like the nasal placode, which is rather
lateral, will come to integrate towards the midline
and this is where you have
this entire midline forming on the anterior section,
which is ultimately a midline of anticipation.
You have a whole area of anticipation, of probability.
I have here this entire phase of integration like this,
which we call the flow of the neural crest.
That is to say, from the posterior mesencephalon,
rhombomere,
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, which completely comes, like this, to invade,
to integrate the mesoderm to form ectoderm,
which we call the flow of the neural crest.
And it will completely invade throughout the face, this entire area, at
the level of the visceral system, up to here.
It’s truly a flow like this.
At the same time, I have this movement of development of my brain.
At the same time, I have all these dural sheaths organizing here, like this, you
see.
And at the same moment, I have my entire anterior line, little by little, taking shape.
So here, I've drawn in orange the entire superficial area
to the depth.
This is what we call mesoderm.
Skin here is not the same thing.
It’s a part of the muscles, the bones, etc.
The cornea, yellow like this at the level of water.
the eye, etc. is an integration.